Hello and welcome to English learning
hub.
English listening test designed for A2
learners.
This test consists of 30 questions which
are divided into six parts. I will give
you a short instruction at the beginning
of each part.
Before we get started, take a pen and
paper so you can take notes while
listening.
Are you ready? Let's get started.
Part one. Listen to a description of a
famous painting, Nighthawks.
So, the painting we're looking at now is
called Nighthawks by the American artist
Edward Hopper, who was born in 1882.
Hopper finished the painting in 1942.
Nighthawks came to Chicago a short time
after that. As you can see, the painting
is a scene in an American cafe late at
night. There are three customers.
They're sitting at the bar. The
customers look like strangers. They
aren't looking at each other and they
aren't talking. There's also a
bartender. He's busy behind the bar and
he isn't talking to his customers
either. It's quite a lonely scene. The
New York street outside the cafe is very
dark. It's very bright inside the cafe,
but it doesn't look warm and friendly in
there at all. The word nighthawk, like
night owl, describes a person who stays
up late. So, the three people at the bar
are like nighthawks. The two men are
wearing dark suits and hats. One of the
men is smoking. He's sitting next to a
woman. She's wearing a red dress with
short sleeves. She has lovely long red
hair. She looks pretty, but she isn't
smiling. As you can see, the bartender
is wearing a white jacket and a white
hat. He's looking outside. Maybe he
wants to go home.
Choose the correct option.
[Music]
part two. Listen to five conversations.
Where are the people in each
conversation?
Match the conversations with the places.
There are two answers you don't need.
How often do you come and watch a movie
here?
Every Saturday night.
Really? That's a lot. Well, I hope this
movie is good.
Yes. Oh, everyone's going in now. Let's
go in and find our seats.
What are you looking for?
A skirt and a jacket. I need some new
clothes for work. Do you like this
jacket?
Yes. Oh, look. I love that blue dress.
Let's try them on quickly. The store is
closing in 10 minutes.
So, what's your new girlfriend like?
Well, she's shy until you get to know
her. She's very hardworking, too.
She's just like you, then. Oh, sorry.
This is my station. I have to get off
here.
Oh, okay. See you on the train tomorrow
morning. Bye.
Where did you study English before?
At a school in Madrid. My teacher was
really nice and I learned a lot.
Do you like our teacher here?
Yes, he's really fun.
Let's do this speaking exercise now.
Yes. Okay.
What does your boyfriend look like?
He's very tall and thin. He has
beautiful blue eyes, short blonde hair.
Hm, he sounds nice. Oh, here's my boss.
I'm going to my desk. See you later.
Okay. I have a meeting now anyway.
Choose the correct option.
[Music]
Hey, hey, hey.
Down.
[Music]
Do you
Part three. Listen to an interview and
take notes.
Excuse me. Good morning. I'm from Smart
Travel Magazine. Can I ask you a few
questions?
Air? Yes, that's fine.
Where are you from?
I'm from the US. New York, actually.
And what are your plans in the UK?
Well, I'm on business. I'm a clothing
designer. I come to the UK twice a year
for London Fashion Week.
And is that happening this week?
Yes, it is. I'm meeting some people this
afternoon and I have a photo shoot
tonight.
You're going to be busy?
Yes, I am. But I'm going to have fun,
too.
And how long are you staying in London?
Well, I'm in London for a week. Then I'm
going to fly to Ireland for a week's
vacation.
That sounds nice. What are you going to
do there?
I'm going to visit my grandmother. She's
95 years old.
Oh, that's nice. Enjoy your stay. Thank
you.
Choose the correct answer.
[Music]
Happy
people.
[Music]
Part four. Listen to five conversations.
Match the conversations with what the
speakers are planning to do.
[Laughter]
What time are you going to the airport?
Well, my flight's at 10:30, so I'm
leaving home at 6:00. And how are you
getting there?
By taxi. My company pays for it.
I'm going to be really busy next week.
Oh, why is that?
I'm going to a conference in Turkey.
Oh, that sounds exotic. What kind of
conference?
It's a conference for NOS's.
What are you going to do after college,
Michael?
I'm going to teach English in India. Oh,
that's amazing. I'd love to go to India.
Well, come and visit me next year.
What are we going to do today?
I'd like to go biking in the woods. Do
you want to come?
Air. Yes, that'll be fun, but I've got
no sense of direction.
Oh, don't worry about it. I have my
smartphone with me.
Do you have any plans for the weekend?
Yes, it's my girlfriend's birthday. I'm
staying at home and cooking dinner for
her.
What are you making?
Oh, something easy. Pasta, I think.
[Music]
away.
We are
[Music]
Heat. Hey, Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Hi, James. I'm home. Did you have a good
day at school?
Not bad. Mom, there's nothing in the
house to eat. I'm really hungry.
I've just been shopping. Dinner is in
half an hour. By the way, have you
cleaned your room yet?
Mom, I've been at school all day and now
I have a lot of homework. I've picked up
my dirty clothes, though.
Okay, thanks, James. Maybe you can clean
your room later. Can you set the table
for dinner now? And when you finish
doing that, can you take out the garbage
for me?
All right. All right. I'm going.
James, don't look so bored. Please.
There's a lot of housework to do and I
can't do it all.
I realize that, Mom. I've got a lot of
homework to finish. That's all.
And I've got a lot of other things to do
as well.
Sorry, Mom. I know.
Okay, let's just do the boring things
and then we can sit down and have a nice
dinner.
Yeah. Okay, sounds good.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
I have actually. I went to one last
Saturday night.
Oh, so did you wear anything fun?
I went as Mickey Mouse. Nobody knew it
was me.
Have you done your homework yet,
Melissa?
Yeah, I've already done it, Dad.
Okay, that's good. What was it today?
I wrote something about celebrities and
fashion. It was really interesting.
Have you ever bought something you've
never worn?
Yes, I have. I bought some beautiful
designer boots last year. The problem
was they didn't really fit. I just
wanted to buy them because they were
fantastic boots. They're still under my
bed.
Oh, Jessica. Jessica, please don't tell
anyone.
I'm looking for an interesting book to
read. Have you read anything interesting
recently?
Well, I've just finished The Shadow of
the Wind by Carlos Ruiz Zafon. I really
enjoyed it. Have you read it?
No, I haven't. What's it like? It's a
really good story. In fact, when I
started reading it, I couldn't stop.
Mary, have you ever been shopping in a
foreign city?
Yes, I have. I went to Berlin last
summer. I went shopping on the Kudam.
It's like Fifth Avenue in New York.
Were the stores good?
Oh, yes. The Quam has really good
stores, and I love shopping somewhere
new.
[Music]
Heat.
Hey, Heat.
[Music]
you. Hallelujah.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]